# Thomas Nevin K

# Senior Engineer

🔀 nevinthomas6767@gmail.com 📞 +91-8714414525

• Trivandrum, India

https://github.com/Nevin06 in https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomas-nevin-k/

https://nevin06.github.io/ https://www.hackerrank.com/nevinthomas6767?hr\_r=1

#### **Profile**

Proficient Engineer with 3 years of experience in Vehicle Diagnostics, Web, and Application domain catering to clients the likes of Jaguar Land Rover. A coder keen on applying the technical expertise gained so far to provide solutions to challenging problems.

## **Professional Experience**

DotNet Developer, Dcube.Ai

03.2023 - present | Trivandrum, India

## Roles & Responsibilities:

Login Page and Admin Dashboard Backend Development using ASP.NET Web APIs

Senior Engineer, Tata Elxsi 10.2019 - 08.2022 | Trivandrum, India

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

Domain Knowledge Fundamentals, Defect-free implementation, and Conformance to Quality assurance standards

Skills: C# · ASP.NET MVC · Microsoft SOL Server · Workbench · MySQL · SQLite · SQL Server Management Studio · CSHTML · XAML · Tortoise SVN · Git

### **Certificates**

- ASP.NET MVC : Complete Practical Guide (.NET 7) C# Web Dev
- .NET Programming for Beginners Windows Forms with C#
- ASP.NET Core Web API Bootcamp Build REST APIs with C# .NET
- Build ASP.NET Core Web API Scratch To Finish (.NET 6 API)
- University of Michigan | Interactivity with JavaScript
- freeCodeCamp (New) Responsive Web Design

#### Education

## BTech in Computer Science and Engineering,

TKM College of Engineering 08.2015 - 06.2019 | Kollam, India CGPA: 7.64/10.0

#### **Skills**

- Authentication · Microsoft SQL Server · Entity Framework (EF) Core · Authorization · ASP.NET MVC · Domain Modeling · .NET 7 · WYSIWYG Lavout Tools · C#
- SQLite · Azure API Management · Middleware · Minimal Web API · Entity Framework (EF) Core · .NET Core · SQL · OAuth 2.0 · Language Integrated Query (LINQ) · ASP.NET Web API · Azure Hosting · .NET 7 · C# · Design Patterns
- Event Handling · Program Deployment · WinForms · Visual Studio · .NET Framework · Multithreading · C#
- Authentication · Dependency Injection · JSON Web Token (JWT) · Swagger API · Entity Framework (EF) Core · Authorization · . NET Core · SQL · Domain Modeling · Postman API · AutoMapper · Git · ASP.NET Web API · Representational State Transfer (REST). ASP.NET Core · Design Patterns
- HTML5 · CSS3 · JavaScript

## Interests

# Complete Web Developer in 2023: Zero to Mastery

Pursuing my career path of becoming a React Developer

## **ChatGPT AI Voice Chatbot Build with React and FAST API combo**

Learning how to develop a Human Sounding Voice Assistant that speaks any language from Udemy